Guide to the E. Roy Weintraub Papers, 1930-2019 and undated RL.11763
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1930-2012; undated; 3
  - Articles, Book Chapters, and Other Papers, 1969-2012; undated; 1
    - Fortune Encyclopedia: Neoclassical, 1992 (Box 4)
      Copy, drafts, and related correspondence
    - Full Employment Model: A Critique, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
      Reprint, drafts, and related correspondence for joint paper with S. Weintraub
    - Full Employment Model: A Reply, 1974 (Box 4)
    - General Competitive Analysis, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
      Drafts and related correspondence for review of book by Arrow and Hahn
    - General Equilibrium Theory, 1973-1976; 2 folders (Box 4)
      Reprint, drafts, and related correspondence for contribution to volume edited by S. Weintraub
    - Historical Case Studies Are Made, Not Given, 1986-1989 (Box 4)
      Draft and related correspondence
    - How Should We Write the History of Twentieth-Century Economics, 1999 (Box 5)
      Reprint and related correspondence
    - Inflation-Unemployment Model, 1971; undated (Box 5)
    - Is Is-A-Precursor-Of A Transitive Relation, 1994 (Box 5)
      Correspondence related to publication
    - JEL Essay, 2016-2017 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - Keynes's Employment Function: Comment on Wells, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Lionel McKenzie and the Proof of the Existence of a Competitive Equilibrium, 1999-2012 (Box 5)
      Related correspondence and research materials
    - Making Economic Knowledge: Reflections on Golinski's Constructivist History of Science, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Making Up History: A Comment on Pratten, 2004 (Box 5)
    - McCarthy, 2015-2017 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - Methodology Doesn't Matter But the History of Thought Might, 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Microeconomic Foundations of Macroeconomic Theory: A Critical Survey, 1974-1978; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Microfoundations, The Compatibility of Microeconomics and Macroeconomics, 1979-1985; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Draft and related correspondence, including follow-up correspondence with Clower, Leijonhufvud, Shubik, and others
    - Neo-Walrasian Program is Empirically Progressive, 1985 (Box 5)
    - On a Formula of Harrod's, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
      Draft and related correspondence with Harrod
    - On Convergence to Pareto Allocations, 1970-1975; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - On Stability, Equilibrium, and Optimal System Size, 1970-1972; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - On the Brittleness of the Orange Equilibrium, 1988 (Box 5)
    - On the Existence of a Competitive Equilibrium: 1930-1954, 1982-1985 (Box 5)
      Reprint, proofs, draft, and related correspondence
    - On the Size of Blocking Coalitions, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - On the Synthesis of General Systems, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Palgrave Pieces, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
      Drafts of Palgrave contributions on Martin Bronfenbrenner and Abraham Wald
    - Papers with Ted Gayer, 1998-1999; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Drafts, research materials, and related correspondence for two papers: Negotiating at the Boundary: Patinkin v Phipps; and Equilibrium Proofmaking
    - PAS Review, 2015 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - Potpourri: The Monetarist Papers, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Pure and the Applied: Bourbakism Comes to Mathematical Economics, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
    - Recent Economic Thought: General Equilibrium, 1990 (Box 6)
      Includes correspondence and research materials for invitation to edit volume on general equilibrium theory
    - Recollections, 1998-2019 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - Review of Aumann and Shapley, Values of Non-Atomic Games, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Review of Benassy, Macroeconomics: An Introduction to the Non-Walrasian Approach, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Review of Davis and Hersch, The Mathematical Experience, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Review of Dore et al., John von Neumann and Modern Economics, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Review of Dow, Macroeconomic Thought: A Methodological Approach, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - Review of Harcourt, The Microeconomic Foundations of Macroeconomics, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Review of Katzner, Analysis Without Measurement, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Review of Klein, The Role of Economic Theory, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Review of McCloskey, The Rhetorical Turn in Economics, 1992 (Box 6)
      Correspondence related to review
    - Review of Mills, Optimisation in Economic Analysis, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Review of Nasar, A Beautiful Mind, 1999 (Box 6)
    - Review of Nikaido, Monopolistic Competition and Effective Demand, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Review of Porter, Trust in Numbers, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Review of Redman, Economics and the Philosophy of Science, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Review of Stigum, Toward a Formal Science of Economics, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Review of Telser, Economic Theory and the Core, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Review of Walsh and Gram, Classical and Neoclassical Theories of General Equilibrium, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Review of Whitaker, The Correspondence of Alfred Marshall, 1997 (Box 6)
    - Reviews of Weintraub's Writings, 1979-1994; undated (Box 6)
      Includes copies of reviews of Weintraub's published works
    - Roger Backhouse's Straw Herring, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Successes and Failures of Macroeconomic Policy, 1980; undated (Box 6)
    - Stability of Stochastic General Equilibrium Systems, 1969 (Box 6)
      Copy of dissertation
    - Stability Theory via Liapunov's Method: A Note on the Contribution of Takuma Yasui, 1985-1992; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Reprint, drafts, research materials, and related correspondence
    - Stochastic Stability of a General Equilibrium Model, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
    - Stochastic Stability of a General Equilibrium System Under Adaptive Expectations, 1971 (Box 6)
      Reprint, draft, research materials, and related correspondence
    - Stochastic Stability of Short-Run Market Equilibrium: Comment, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
    - Substantive Mountains and Methodological Molehills, Response to Dow, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
      Draft, research materials, and related correspondence
    - Trader-Commodity Parity Theorem, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Transaction Costs and the Convergence of a Trade Out of Equilibrium Adjustment Process, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - Transactions Middleman is Inefficient, 1973-1976 (Box 6)
    - Uncertainty and Product Safety, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - Uncertainty and the Keynesian Revolution, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Work In Progress, 2011-2019 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - Zeeman's Unstable Stock Exchange, 1979-1983 (Box 7)
  - Books, 1930-2011; undated; 2
    This subseries includes drafts, research materials, and correspondence for books written by Weintraub. Files are arranged alphabetically by title. Copies of Weintraub's books can be found in the current catalog for the Perkins/Bostock Library.
    Sub-series contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
    - 2002 Book HEBMS, 1992-2009 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - An Approach to General Equilibrium Dynamics, 1972-1973; undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Includes draft manuscript and correspondence with Robert Clower and others about draft manuscript
    - An Introduction to Game Theory in Economics, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
      Includes correspondence about draft manuscript
    - Conflict and Cooperation in Economics, 1973-1975 (Box 7)
      Includes correspondence related to book manuscript
    - Coordination and Catastrophe, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
      Includes drafts and related correspondence
    - Duppe-Weintraub Book, 2013-2019 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - General Equilibrium Analysis: Studies in Appraisal, 1980-2000; 4 folders (Box 7)
      Includes draft materials, figures and diagrams, research materials, and related correspondence
    - Historiography, 2015-2019 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - How Economics Became a Mathematical Science, 1930-2004; 5 folders (Box 7)
      Includes draft materials, book proposal, research materials, family photographs used in book, related correspondence, and reviews of the book
    - Mathematics for Economists, 1981-1983 (Box 7)
      Includes draft materials, research materials, and related correspondence
    - Stabilizing Dynamics, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Includes draft chapters and research materials
    - Stabilizing Dynamics, 1987-2011; 6 folders (Box 8)
      Includes draft chapters and other materials, research materials, related correspondence, and reviews of book
    - Toward a History of Game Theory, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
      Includes proofs, related correspondence, and review of book edited by Weintraub
  - History of Political Economy (HOPE), 1989-1994; 3
    This subseries includes draft materials, editor's introductions, and correspondence from Weintraub's service as an editor and associate editor of the journal History of Political Economy. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Feminist Theory and the History of Economic Thought, 1993 (Box 8)
      Editor's introduction to minisymposium
    - History of Economics and the History of Science, 1992 (Box 8)
    - HOPE 2001, 1999-2001 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - HOPE 2017 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - HOPE - Editorial, 1989-1993 (Box 8)
      Includes routine correspondence related to journal business and establishment of the Economists' Papers Archive
    - HOPE Minisymposium, 2017-2018 (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0002)
    - Keynes Lives in Several Communities, 1991-1994; 2 folders (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence about minisymposium with Bradley Bateman and editor's introduction
    - Locating Marx After the Fall: Brewer-Marx Minisymposium, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence related to journal issue
    - Reconstructing Economic Knowledge, 1991 (Box 8)
- Research and Notes, 1890-2012; undated; 4
  This series includes materials from Weintraub's research. Files include notes, interview transcripts, relevant correspondence, and writings by others used in research. Of note is a transcript of an interview with Gerard Debreu.
  - Research, 1976-2012; undated; 1
    This subseries includes notes, interview transcripts, and relevant correspondence used in Weintraub's research. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Arrow Book - Dead, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence and materials for proposed book on Kenneth Arrow that was not written
    - Audio Recording of Weintraub-Debreu Interview, 1992 (Box 12)
      Recording of Weintraub's interview with Gerard Debreu on three microcassette tapes.
      Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services to request the production of use copies.
      - Weintraub-Debreu Interview: Tape 1, 1992 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL11763-CS-0001)
      - Weintraub-Debreu Interview: Tape 2, 1992 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL11763-CS-0002)
      - Weintraub-Debreu Interview: Tape 3, 1992 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL11763-CS-0003)
    - Cartels and Power, 1976-1979 (Box 8)
      Includes research notes
    - Catastrophe Theory and Economics, 1980-1995 (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence related to potential project
    - MIT Economics in the Postwar Era, 2010-2012 (Box 8)
      Includes research materials and correspondence with Robert Solow on the history of the economics department at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)
    - Proofs of Competitive Equilibrium, 1993-2011; undated; 6 folders (Box 8)
      Includes files for research on the history of proofs of existence of competitive (or general) equilibrium
    - Stability of Equilibrium, 1985-1988 (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence with Hirofumi Uzawa, Lionel McKenzie, and others related to research project
    - Transcript of Interview with Gerard Debreu, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Writings by Others, 1890-1991; 2
    This subseries includes select scholarly writings by others used as reference materials in Weintraub's research. Includes many volumes once owned by Sidney Weintraub. Files are arranged alphabetically.
    - Arrow, Limits of Organization, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Arrow, Social Choice and Individual Values, 1951 (Box 8)
    - Bohm-Bawerk, Capital and Interest, 1890 (Box 9)
    - Brems, Product Equilibrium under Monopolistic Competition, 1951 (Box 9)
    - Cowles Fiftieth Anniversary, 1991 (Box 9)
      Collected volume celebrating 50th anniversary of Cowles Foundation
    - Empoli, Theory of Economic Equilibrium, 1931 (Box 9)
    - Fisher, A Statistical Method for Measuring Marginal Utility and Testing the Justice of a Progressive Income Tax, 1927 (Box 9)
    - Fossati, Essays in Dynamics and Econometrics, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Frisch, Propagation Problems and Impulse Problems in Dynamic Economics, 1933 (Box 9)
    - Gide and Rist, Histoire des Doctrines Economique, 1926 (Box 9)
    - Hicks, Theory of Wages, 1932 (Box 9)
    - Hicks, Theorie Mathematique de la Valeur, 1937 (Box 9)
    - Irish Pound, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Klein, An Essay on the Theory of Economic Prediction, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Kuhn and Tucker, Contributions to the Theory of Games, 1950 (Box 9)
    - Lange, Price Flexibility and Employment, 1944 (Box 9)
    - Lindbeck, Monetary-Fiscal Analysis and General Equilibrium, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Makower, Activity Analysis and the Theory of Economic Equilibrium, 1957 (Box 9)
    - McCloskey, Writing of Economics, 1987 (Box 9)
    - McKinsey, Introduction to the Theory of Games, 1952 (Box 9)
    - Morishima, Dynamic Economic Theory, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Patinkin, On the Nature of the Monetary Mechanism, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Porter, Ted and Norton Wise, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
      Includes copies of writings by the two authors grouped together
    - Robinson Collected Papers, 1951-1973; 3 folders (Box 10)
      Includes volumes 1, 2, and 4 of Joan Robinson's collected writings
    - Robinson, Economics of Imperfect Competition, 1934 (Box 10)
    - Shephard, Cost and Production Frontiers, 1953 (Box 10)
    - Stackelberg, Theory of the Market Economy, 1952 (Box 10)
    - Tinbergen, A Method and its Application to Investment Activity, 1939 (Box 10)
    - Tinbergen, Les Fondements Mathematiques de la Stabilisation du Movement des Affaires, 1938 (Box 10)
    - Viner, Cost Curves and Supply Curves, undated (Box 10)
    - von Neumann and Morgenstern, Theory of Games and Economic Behavior, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Yntoma, A Mathematical Reformulation of the General Theory of International Trade, 1932 (Box 10)
- Academia, 1980-2019
  Series contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - References and Referee, 1980-2019; 323 files; approximately 100 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0003)
    Includes primarily document files in MS Word, WordPerfect, PDF, rich text, and plain text formats. Also includes audio files in WAV vormat and a still image file in JPEG format.
    FERPA information restricted until 2094.
    Personnel information restricted until 2094.
  - Roy's CV, 2015; 1 file; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0001)
    Includes a document file in MS Word format.
  - Science Studies, 1996-2014; 77 files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0003)
    Includes document files in WordPerfect, MS Word, HTML, and rich text formats.
    Personnel information restricted until 2089.
  - Teaching, 1980-2014; 135 files; approximately 25 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11763-SET-0003)
    Includes web files (HTML format), document files (MS Word, WordPerfect, plain text, PDF, and MS Excel formats), and still image files (JPEG format).
    FERPA information restricted until 2089.